（サイ）ナルト　また　みんなに
チャクラを渡せないのかい？
Naruto…
Can you share your chakra
with everyone again?
（ナルト）今は無理だ。
I can't right now!
Kurama hasn't finished
amassing chakra yet!
九喇嘛のチャクラが
まだ溜まりきってねえ。
本体を倒すには
あのデカブツをなぎ払いつつ→
In order to take down
the main body,
we need to mow down the big ones
and slip past them.
間をすり抜けていくしか方法が…。
一気にジャンプして
近づける距離でもない。
The distance is too great to
make a single leap for it.
敵の攻撃を弾き→
We also need time to weave signs
and repel the enemy's attacks.
印を結ぶ時間もいる。
ナルトのチャクラがない以上→
Without your chakra, Naruto,
it's very likely we'll suffer
heavy casualties.
深手を負う可能性が高いのに→
And the Medical Corps can't
come up to the front.
医療班は　前に出られない。
（サスケ）なぎ払い　すり抜ける
何の造作もない。
Mow down and slip past?
Easy.
一気にジャンプして近づけるうえに→
This guy has the power to clear
the distance in a single leap
攻撃も弾く力もあんぜ　こいつは。
and repel enemy attacks.
（サクラ）みんなが深手を負っても→
I can now stay nearby and
heal anyone who suffers
serious injuries at all times.
常にそばにいて
回復してあげられる　今の私なら。
（３人）口寄せの術。
- Summoning Jutsu!
- Summoning Jutsu! - Summoning Jutsu!
The New Three-Way Deadlock
Huh?
あれ　ん？
Wait…
この色。
This color…
You're…
お前…　ガマ吉じゃねえかよ。
Gamakichi!
（ガマ吉）親父は
今　手打ちのゴタゴタじゃけん→
Pop was tied up with
some negotiations,
so I came in his place.
俺が来たで　びっくりしたか？
You surprised?!
No! No!
いや…　いや　いや　いや　いや…。
But man, you sure got big
all of a sudden!
それより
一気にでかくなったな　お前。
赤丸んときより
びっくりしたってばよ。
I'm more shocked than
I was about Akamaru!
お前ら人間の成長が
遅すぎるんじゃ！
You humans grow too slow, that's all.
それより　用件は何じゃ？
Anyway, what's up?
Right!
おう　奥のほうに
でっけえのがいんだろ。
See the gigantic guy way
in the back?
Could you get me closer to it
with a big leap?
あれに大ジャンプで近づいてくれ。
（ガマ吉）あの　いちばんでかいのか？
You mean the biggest one
over there?
Yeah.
ああ。
（アオダ）サスケ様　いかように？
Lord Sasuke, your desire?
お前は
まっすぐに進むだけでいい。
I need you to just keep
advancing forward.
奥の本体は　俺がやる。
I'll get the real body in the back!
（カツユ）サクラちゃん　ついに→
Sakura dear!
You've finally able to invoke
the 100 Healings Mark!
百豪の印を発動できたのですね。
綱手様も　きっとお喜びに。
Lady Tsunade would be so proud…
（サクラ）カツユ様　今は　それより→
Lady Katsuyu, we don't have time…
分裂して　連合のみんなに
１人ずつついてください。
Please divide and attend to each person
in the Allied Shinobi Forces.
Our role will be to heal everyone.
私たちは　回復役です。
（ミナト）まさか　もう一度→
I never expected
to see the Three-Way Deadlock
Summoning again!
口寄せ三竦みが見られるとは
思わなかったな。
フフッ…。
It is a new era!
《新たな時代よ…》
行け！
Go!
Go! Aoda!
行け　アオダ。
お願いします　カツユ様。
Lady Katsuyu, please proceed!
ジャンプだ　ガマ吉。
Jump, Gamakichi!
クッ…。
《これが元の七班…》
This is the original Team 7…
いいぞ　ガマ吉！
だてにでかくなってねえな。
Nice, Gamakichi!
Your size isn't just for show, eh!
そがいなことよりのう→
Nevermind that, just hurry up
and weave your jutsu signs!
はよう術の印を結べっちゃ
ほんまに。
オラオラ　頭から振り落とすぞ。
Get with it,
or I'll shake you off my head.
Even his attitude has gotten bigger!
《態度は　更にでかく》
わかってるってばよ！
I know!
うわっ！　なっ　なんだ！？
What's going on?
It's all right.
大丈夫　このナメクジは
五代目火影の回復術です。
These slugs are part
of the Fifth Hokage's Healing Jutsu.
心配しないでください。
Please do not worry.
My strength is being restored!
《力が　戻ってくる》
傷が。
治癒して。
My wounds are…
It's healing me…
《さっき　百豪の印を
発動したばかりなのに→
Her 100 Healings Mark was
only just activated!
カツユ様の遠隔治癒まで
こなすなんて→
And yet she can already perform
Lady Katsuyu's long-distance healing!
サクラ　あんたって子は
ほんとにもう！》
Sakura… You are simply amazing!
（アオダ）サスケ様。
Lord Sasuke?
そのまま行け。
Keep moving forward.
サスケ！
Sasuke!
《キバ：いきやがれ！》
《シノ：やれ！》
Go for it!
Do it!
《ヒナタ：頑張って！》
《シカマル：よく狙え》
Hang in there!
Aim well!
You can do it!
《チョウジ：いけるよ！》
《いの：やっちゃえ！》
Give it to 'em!
《うん！》
Yes!
風遁　超大玉螺旋手裏剣！
Wind Style: Massive Rasen Shuriken!
炎遁　須佐能乎加具土命！
Inferno Style: Susano'o Flame Control!
((俺ってば
サスケとの相性よかったんだな。
Sasuke and I must've been
compatible, after all…
（ヤマト）ああ　雷に勝てるのは
風だけだ。
Yes…
Only "Wind" can beat "Lightning."
(いや　そっちじゃなくて))
No…
That's not what I meant.
((火を助けて
更に大きな力にできるのは→
Only "Wind" can assist
and magnify "Fire"…
(風の力だけだってことだ))
当たった！
本当に当たったぞ！
It's hit!
It really hit!
《扉間：あれほどの加具土命を
見た覚えがない。
I don't recall ever seeing
a Flame Control of that magnitude.
まったく同じチャクラ比で
術を合わせたか》
And they combined jutsu
with matching chakra ratios!
熟年のコンビでも難しいぞ。
That's difficult even for
a seasoned duo!
風車のような手裏剣に
漆の光沢より黒い矢。
A windmill-like shuriken,
and an arrow blacker than lacquer…
名付けて
灼遁　光輪疾風漆黒矢零式！
Let's name it
the Scorch Style Nimbus Gale
Jet Black Arrow Formation Zero!
フッ　いや　ないな。
Nah, never mind.
ヘッ！
燃え尽きろ。
Burn away…
サスケの言ったこと
キミも　見て聞いていただろう。
You heard what
Sasuke said earlier, didn't you?
彼の本当の狙いは　なんなんだ。
What are his true intentions?
（重吾）さあな。
I have no idea.
《香燐：クソ！　なんでサスケと
別行動なんだよ！
Damn it!
Why did we branch off from Sasuke?
話が違くねえ？》
This wasn't the deal!
《水月：助かった　最前線なんて
まっぴらごめんだっつうの》
I'm safe!
No thanks to being on the frontlines!
（大蛇丸）あそこね。
There they are.
（大蛇丸）
ずいぶんなザマね…　綱手。
Look at the sorry state
you're in, Tsunade.
（水月）げぇ～　でっかいナメクジ！
Gross… A gigantic slug…
倒すのに　塩どんだけいるかな。
How much salt would
you need to take it down?
あれは　湿骨林から
口寄せされたカツユの　ほんの一部。
That's just one part of Katsuyu
that was summoned from
Shikkotsu Woods.
あれでも　すごく小さいほうよ。
へぇ～。
I'd say it's pretty small, actually.
You don't say.
今は　ナメクジより
五影のことだろ。
I thought we were here
for the Five Kage, not the slugs.
Lord Orochimaru,
stop paying attention to Suigetsu
大蛇丸様も　いちいち
そいつの言うこと→
気にしないでいいからさ。
さっさと用事済ませてさ。
and get to the task at hand.
サスケ君と離して
こっちに連れてきたのが→
Are you that upset because
you couldn't stay with Sasuke?
そんなに不服？
そのとおり…　じゃねえよし！
That's totally…not the case!
さっさ行くの…　水月てめえ！
Let's just do this.
Damn you, Suigetsu!
Why are you picking on me?
なんで僕が責められんの？
ナメクジ見たら
塩かけたくなるもんでしょ→
Doesn't everyone who sees
a slug want to sprinkle salt on it?
誰だって。
（大蛇丸）まずは　綱手ね。
Tsunade first!
行くわよ。
Let's go.
Lady Tsunade!
（カツユ）綱手様！
あれ？　火影って
ばばあだったっけ？
Wait, was the Hokage
always a granny?
うげっ！　これって
胴長じゃないもんね…　やっぱ。
Ugh…
It's not like she had a really
long torso either, right?
無茶をしたようね　綱手。
It seems you were reckless, Tsunade.
（綱手）大蛇丸…。
Orochimaru?
Katsuyu…
カツユ　私は五影の処置をしに
ここへ来た。
I came here to aid the Five Kage.
敵じゃないわ。
I'm not an enemy.
信じられる根拠がありません。
I have no reason to believe you.
それに　あなたは死んだはずです。
Besides, you were dead!
うぅっ！
怪しい行動をしたと思うなら→
If I do anything that
strikes you as suspect,
酸で　今度こそ
ほんとに殺すといいわ。
you're welcome to kill me
once and for all with your acid.
ひ～っ！
わかりました
あなたを信じましょう。
All right.
I'll believe you.
マンダと違って　ものわかりがいい。
You're quite sensible, unlike Manda.
さて…　ではまず。
Now then…
First of all…
（大蛇丸）他の影たちはどこ？
Where are the other Kage?
私の分裂体の中で　回復中です。
They're recovering inside
my fragments.
皆さん重傷で　なかなか…。
They sustained serious injuries,
and it's very…
（大蛇丸）
しかし　カツユ　あなたがいて→
But Katsuyu…
With you here, why is it taking
so long for them to heal?
なぜ回復がこの程度なの？
私は　綱手様の百豪の力に呼応して
力を使うことができます。
I can only use my power
in response
to the strength of
Lady Tsunade's 100 Healings.
（カツユ）今の綱手様は
すごく弱っておいでで→
But Lady Tsunade is
extremely weak right now,
私の力を
十分に発動できないのです。
so I'm not able to activate
my strength fully.
そういうシステムだったかしら…。
Is that how the system worked?
まぁ　よく思い出してみても→
Anyway, whatever I remember,
I've never seen Tsunade so weak.
ここまで弱った綱手を
初めて見るから　そうなのね。
So it must be true.
口寄せが解けかかっているのを
どうにか　こらえつつ→
I am trying to persevere
and focus on healing,
despite the Summoning
starting to unravel.
回復に集中している状態です。
（カツユ）なので　綱手様の体を
上手くつなげることもできず…。
That's why I haven't been able
to properly reattach her body.
水月　綱手の下半身を持って
上半身とつなげなさい。
Suigetsu, bring Tsunade's lower half
and join it to her upper half.
え～っ！？　バラすほうが
得意なんすけど。
Huh?!
I'm better at cutting things up.
うげ～っ。
Ugh…
ナメクジが濡れて　グネグネ気持悪いよ。
The slugs are all slimy
and wriggly. Gross!
そりゃお前もだろうが。
Well, so are you, Suigetsu!
In fact, you're grosser and weirder
because you have a human form!
人型の分
お前のほうが気持悪いし　変だろ。
香燐　あなたは噛ませて
回復させてあげなさい。
Karin…
Let her bite you
so that she can heal.
え～　サスケ以外に噛まれるの
やだなぁ　うち。
What? I don't want anyone
but Sasuke biting me…
あ～　サスケ好きを公言したね　今。
Hah! You just admitted
you're in love with Sasuke!
Huh?
はっ！　ち　違っ　あんなクソ野郎。
You're wrong!
How could I hate,
I mean, like that damn Sasuke?
サスケが…　くね～だろが！
What are you saying?
何言ってんの？
う　うちを殺しかけたのが…。
He tried to kill me…
And it was irresistible…
たまらない…　違うか。
No, it wasn't!
フッ　サスケに噛まれる前から
歯形だらけだろ　キミ。
You were covered in bite marks
long before Sasuke bit you!
うっせえ！
今はサスケ専用なんだよ！
Shut up!
Right now, I'm exclusively for Sasuke.
開き直んな　入れ歯製造機。
Don't be so defiant,
you denture mold model.
Besides, how does
your body work anyway?
だいたい　どういうシステムだよ
キミの体は。
キミのほうが変だろ。
んだと～　こら！
You're the weird one.
What? Say that again!
あなたたち　さっさとなさい。
You two…
Make it snappy.
変なのはお互いさまでしょう。
ケンカはよしなさい。
You're both weird.
So stop fighting.
さもないと　私の蛇で縛り上げ→
Or else…
I'll have my snakes ties you up
口から入り込んで
体を乗っ取るわよ。
and crawl into your mouth
and possess you.
《あんたが
いちばん変なんだよ》
You're the weirdest one
among us all!
He's weird and he's abnormal.
《変態で変体なんだよ》
WEIRD                           ABNORMAL
《吸い取られすぎて
うちが老けそう》
She's taking so much,
I might end up aging into a hag.
綱手様　もう大丈夫です。
Lady Tsunade,
you're going to be all right!
綱手　少しは私に感謝しなさい。
Tsunade, be a little grateful to me.
里を裏切ったお前が今更　なぜだ？
You betrayed the village…
So why all of this now?
今はいろいろと
興味の幅が広がってね。
The range of things that
interest me has expanded.
昔は自らが風となり
風車を回したいと思ってたわ。
In the past, I wanted to become
the wind and turn the windmill myself.
（大蛇丸）でも今は
いつ吹くかもわからない→
But now, I know the pleasure
of waiting around for
someone else's wind.
他の風を待つ楽しさも知れた。
One that is unpredictable.
その風を楽しむ前に
密封されたくはないからね。
And I don't want that wind to
get sealed away before I can enjoy it.
相変わらず訳のわからんことを。
You still don't make any sense.
だが　少し変わったか。
But…I suppose you've changed a little.
まさか　お前に助けられるとはね。
そんなこともあるわよ。
I never imagined you would save me…
Even that is possible.
覚えているか？
あのときの三竦み。
Do you remember?
The Three-Way Deadlock
from that time?
口寄せの…。
The summoning…
違う。　文字通りの三竦み。
No…
Just like how it's written…
The Three-Way Deadlock…
((土遁　岩鉄砲の術！
Earth Style Stone Pistol Jutsu!
（自来也）ハァ　ハァ…。
無駄よ　綱手。
It's useless, Tsunade.
岩隠れの土遁は
やがてこの山を崩す。
The Earth Style of the Hidden Stone
will most likely
cause this mountain to collapse.
逃げるなら猶予はない。
あなたと私なら。
If we're going to escape,
we can't wait.
Just the two of us.
自来也もだ。
Jiraiya…too!
自来也を連れて→
We can't take Jiraiya
and outrun them.
彼らから
脱出することはできないわ。
だから　私が医療忍術を…。
That's why I'll use Medical Ninjutsu to…
綱手　今は戦争よ。
Tsunade, this is war.
不確定な情をさしはさんで
確率を下げたりはできない。
We can't let our emotions
get in the way
and lower the probability of success.
確率って何だ！
And what is success?
私たちが生き残る確率よ。
To survive.
１人ではダメ　２人ならなんとか。
One alone can't. Two probably can.
３人じゃ…　全滅する。
Three spells…
certain death.
あなたは続けてなさい。
Go on ahead.
いいわ　私が自来也を…。
I'll take care of Jiraiya…
一歩でも動けば　私がお前を殺す。
Make one move…and I'll kill you.
どうやら三竦みってとこね。
Seems like we're in
a three-way deadlock.
何を言うの？　あなたと私→
What are you talking about?
It just boils down to who will act first.
どちらが先手を取るかで決まる。
自来也はもう…　うっ。
Jiraiya is already…
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
んん…。
自来也は　お前のことを
心底信用している。
Jiraiya trusts you completely.
お前を竦ませるに十分なほど。
So much so, that it might freeze you
in your tracks.
くだらない。
So foolish!
私は…。
I'll…!
おい　自来也　綱手　大蛇丸！
Hey! Jiraiya, Tsunade, Orochimaru!
(援軍を呼んできたぞ！))
I've brought reinforcements!
人は　変わるものよ。
People can change.
それか　その前に死ぬかの２つ。
Or they die before they do.
It's one or the other.
彼は
そのままで逝っちゃったけど。
Although he died without changing…
最後まで　お前を
信用していたんだろうな。
He probably trusted you
until the very end.
大蛇丸　お前がもっと早く
そうなってくれたなら→
Orochimaru…
If you were like this sooner,
Jiraiya might not have had to die…
自来也も死なずに…。
それはそれで→
And if I had…
自来也が変わってしまったかも。
Jiraiya might have changed too.
私たち三忍がそうだったように→
Like how it was for us,
the Legendary Sannin,
物事は　そう都合よくは
いかないものよ。
things don't always go
the way you want them to.
一枚岩じゃいられない。
We're not made of stone.
Distortions will appear somewhere.
どこかに
ゆがみができるものでしょう。
《だからこそサスケ君の行く末を
見てみたいのかもね。
Perhaps that's why I want
to observe Sasuke's future.
彼の風をゆっくりと待ちながら》
While patiently waiting
for his wind to blow.
まあ　いい。
Fine. I thank you for helping me heal.
回復させてくれたことには
感謝する。
で　戦争のことは知っているのか？
So… Do you know about the war?
もちろん　だからこうして
協力してるのよ　あなたに。
Of course. That's why
I'm helping you out like this.
どれくらい　ここに…。
How long have I been like this?
（カツユ）私が戦況を報告します。
I can report on the battle situation.
お前　どうやって戦場に？
How did you end up on the front?
《そうか　サクラがカツユを》
（大蛇丸）今頃は
新たなる三竦みが→
お披露目されてるんじゃ
ないかしらね。
ん？
じゃあ　私たちはもう行くわ。
あなたは影たちの回復に
集中することね。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
お楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
オープニングを飾るのは
『こんにちは赤ちゃん』。
梓みちよさんです。